<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hosting | Najam Sikander Awan]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/categories/hosting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-28T10:50:29+05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[najam sikander awan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgraded my hosting for .net 4.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2011/08/09/upgraded-my-hosting-for-net-4-0/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-09T10:13:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2011/08/09/upgraded-my-hosting-for-net-4-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been watching Mix11 videos about asp.net mvc3 and felt pretty excited to mingle with these latest bits but I didn't wanted to limit myself to local environment I wanted to know what efforts are required if I am developing with latest stuff one limitation I had that my host always take ages to update server so I had support for .net3.5. I email them about this thing and in reply they told me either wait 6 months or pay $8. Since I was dying to test out EF code first I paid them and within one day my hosting is all updated and now I am running my incomplete demo online :).</p>

<p>Deployment was a little bit scarier as my hosting doesn't come with any publishing/deployment server but if you have vs2010 sp1 then you are in safe hands all you have to do is to click on add deployable dependencies then build your solution and upload using your favorite ftp client.</p>

<p>This far I like MVC3.0 , Nuget and MVC Scaffolding but I am still learning how to scaffold many to many relations or at least leverage scaffolding and then tune it to have many to many relations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally I Have My Own Domain]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2007/09/30/finally-my-own-domain/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-30T19:47:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2007/09/30/finally-my-own-domain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi guyz,</p>

<p>After many days I am back and back for good :) recentlly i purchased a domain name and hosting package, so that i can have my own <a href="http://najamsikander.com" title="Visit my Website now.">website</a> and I want my settings persistent which was not possible in the case of free hosting like in my case my hosting provider remove the mysql database support.</p>

<p>Can't tell you how happy I am after getting my <a href="http://najamsikander.com" title="Visit my Website now.">website</a> up and running its currently in beta state I will design it from scratch as time permits and planning to use table less design. With my <a href="http://najamsikander.com" title="Visit my Website now.">website</a> I have configured a wordpress blog and currently its using a template that I pick form internet after designing my main <a href="http://najamsikander.com" title="Visit my Website now.">website</a> I will design my own wordpress template.</p>

<p>Below is the screen shot of my new <a href="http://najamsikander.com" title="Visit my Website now.">website</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.najamsikander.com" title="Visit my website"><img src="http://najam.files.wordpress.com/2007/09/najam-sikander-awan.thumbnail.png" alt="My website pic" height="183" width="285" /></a></p>

<p>my <a href="http://blog.najamsikander.com" title="Visit my blog now">blog</a> snapshot is give below</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.najamsikander.com" title="first blog design"><img src="http://najam.files.wordpress.com/2007/09/najam-sikander-awan-blog.thumbnail.png" alt="first blog design" height="310" width="254" /></a></p>

<p>please visit <a href="http://www.najamsikander.com" title="Visit my website now.">http://www.najamsikander.com</a>  and for blog please visit <a href="http://www.blog.najamsikander.com" title="Visit my blog now">http://www.blog.najamsikander.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
