<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Development | Najam Sikander Awan]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-28T09:26:29+05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[najam sikander awan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous Integration &amp; Deployment For .Net Projects TL;DR]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2014/12/31/continuous-integration-and-deployment-for-net-projects/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-31T20:05:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2014/12/31/continuous-integration-and-deployment-for-net-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been involved with development of small and large web applications. I have been using latest technologies and tooling but my workflow felt from ancient times. Recently I got much obsessed with automation I thought to improve my development workflow. In my mind I knew I need to do somthing about build process, tests the build, deployment of latest build and notify team members that new code/build is available.</p>

<p>I started looking around, playing with tools from different vendors and finally had a list to explore and get things done. Following are the tools made to my list.</p>

<ul>
<li>PowerShell</li>
<li>Slack</li>
<li>GitLab</li>
<li>TeamCity</li>
<li>Octopus Deployment</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>If you are thinking wow it's alot to get started with automation then I will recommond learning powershell if your using windows and .Net technologies. With powershell only you can do most of things I am about to share with you.</strong></p>

<h2>Problems</h2>

<p>We are using scrum for development with two week sprint cycle to get things out. Short sprints have their benefits but they also kills if you are doing testing and deployment manually and this pain reachs to maximum intensity if you need to to push code to multple servers (Dev, QA, Staging, Production).</p>

<p><img src="http://s3-ec.buzzfed.com/static/enhanced/webdr01/2013/2/20/17/anigif_enhanced-buzz-4131-1361399397-4.gif"/></p>

<p>We have been using some tooling while writing code and communicating with each other and we were missing few tools and that bites us after a while. Following list contains few common tools in use by our local industry:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>TFS and SVN</strong> - for version control</li>
<li>__Vychat &amp; skype - for communication</li>
<li><strong>Zero unit tests</strong> - (well few devs were submiting their forms to check output and called that unit testing. I am not joking.)</li>
<li><strong>Zero integration tests</strong> (Again manual process followed by Devs and QA)</li>
<li><strong>Deployoment using filezilla</strong> (Yes this is the holy grail of deployment)</li>
</ul>


<p>Few team members had major issues with SVN and TFS as souce control specially on non-windows platforms. Since I have been using Git for sometime now and loved it. I recommonded git and knew we can't move ahead without installing local git server. After some research found GitLab that has free option available. We are running GitLab on ubuntu 12.04 box and untill now it's working smoothly.</p>

<p>Co-workers who were bitten by SVN were in love with git and thought it's the only change we needed in our current workflow/tooling. Well that was a mistake.</p>

<p><img src="http://s3-ec.buzzfed.com/static/enhanced/webdr02/2013/2/8/14/anigif_enhanced-buzz-11517-1360352639-1.gif" /></p>

<h4>Who Broke The Code?</h4>

<p>"Is it ok to pull latest code from remote branch?". Gitlab was providing us information about what changed in latest commit and by whome but couldn't singal us about the integratity of the code it has.</p>

<h6>Manual Solution: Push-Pa</h6>

<p>To solve above problem our team agreed to follow a process which dictates that before pushing your code to version control make sure you pull the code first merge it with your local changes. Compile the merged code, test it to check every feature is still working and than push it to remote branch.</p>

<p>Compiling code is no rocket science but it was painful to do it manually against each commit. Team started to feel the burden but keeps doing it infact they name this push-pull excersize as "Push-Pa".</p>

<h6>Real Solution: Teamcity</h6>

<p>I knew teamcity for a while and used it against TFS source control for a big web forms based web applicatoin.</p>

<p>First task at hand was how to integrate teamcity with gitlab server for monitoring latest commits in a specific branch.</p>

<h4>Deployment Nightmare</h4>

<p>Our deployment process was from 80's or 90's if ftp exist back then. When we needed to deploy code, first step was to pull the latest code from source control. Then make changes for server envoirnment (if you miss transforms, and envoirnment checks) in config files and other code which is specific to server envoirnment. Once that's done create a zip file and upload it to server via ftp.</p>

<p>On server we need to unzip the latest code, and create backup of running website. than overwrite files and test to see if deployment works. If its failing restore the backup, if it works pray to God and say thanks for the blessings.</p>

<p><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/18f10fa837406181e2b43e1680187bb6/tumblr_mpg1oe3dK21qjmdwqo1_500.gif" /></p>

<h6>Solution: Octopus Deploy</h6>

<p>There are many solutions out there to handle deployments some also offer integration feature for which we are using teamcity. In few talks related to devops I came across octopus deploy. It felt nice, easy and powerfull best part was they were targeting .net devs.</p>

<p>Our team currently testing octopus deploy and it's linked with our teamcity server. It takes the teamcity compiled output/package and transform the code and settings for our deployment servers. Once code is modified for web servers its uploaded and deployed automatically. Backup against each deployment is managed by octopusdeploy, you can roll back to preview release anytime you want.</p>

<p>Configurations and integrating octopus server with teamcity and gitlab was little hard but I got minimal setup working in fair amount of time. Now its much easire to deploy code and we can develop our project faster, push small changes/fixes frequently while keeping our sanity intact.</p>

<h4>Are We There Yet?</h4>

<p>Achieving continous deployment was fun and I felt good about it, but one problem was still sticking around. Team asking each other if latest code has been deployed I could have setup emails notification on teamcity and octopus but knew different people value email differently. Some will wait for it and read it to get latest updates some will apply filter so these kind of emails skip their inbox.</p>

<p><img src="http://media.giphy.com/media/XUR9XH8olimic/giphy.gif" /></p>

<p>In my view having these updates inside team chat room was the best option but it's hard to integrate notfications with vychat or skype. This is why my first mission was to convert each member to slack and enforce everyone is using it. (still working on that front)</p>

<p>Slack offers integration points and rest api, using their api our octopus server pushes updates about deployment like if deployment is successful or failed. After deployment notification another notification about same release updates team chat room for somke tests(powershell scripts) status.</p>

<h6>Smoke Testing</h6>

<p>Our current web application under development has many pages of different nature like public pages, secure pages, rediret pages and error pages.</p>

<p>One time we got complaint that one or two public pages are not working for users. Another time pages that suppose to be secure and ask for user credentials were open to everyone. Even though we have QA department and they take proper time to test still these issues could have crawled back. To avoid future compalints in this area I have developed a powershell script that has list of pages (public, secure, 404, 500) and it make requests to those pages and according to response it pushes notifications to slack. That powershell script is executed by Octopus on remote server after each deployment.</p>

<p><img src="http://33.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m2yyycfgnj1r2optzo1_500.gif"/></p>

<h2>Source Control: GitLab</h2>

<h2>Installing TeamCity</h2>

<h2>Installing Octopus Deploy</h2>

<h2>Configurations</h2>

<h2>Results</h2>

<h3>Envoirnment</h3>

<p>To adopt a new modern workflow my baseline envoirment includes teamcity and octopus deploy on windows 8.1 box. Our gitlab is configured with ubuntu 12.04 box.</p>

<p>Download teamcity and octpus deploy setups files from following:</p>

<ul>
<li>TeamCity Setup</li>
<li>Octopus Deploy Sever</li>
<li>Octopus Deploy Tenticle</li>
<li>Ocotpus Deploy Teamcity Plugin</li>
</ul>


<h3>Installing teamcity</h3>

<p>Installation is fairly simple and for database I wanted to use Microsoft SQL Server for that teamcity installation wizard guides you to <a href="http://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/TCD9/Setting+up+an+External+Database#SettingupanExternalDatabase-MicrosoftSQLServer">download SQL JDBC driver</a>. Unzip the file and look for a file <em>4.0.jar</em> copy this file to lib foder of teamcity installation directory.</p>

<p>Now check your teamcity installation wizard and test if drivers are loaded. If there are no errors you can now specifiy connection detail for your sql server database.</p>

<p>After database setup teamcity will prompt you for terms and conditions and then ask you to create admin account.</p>

<h4>Creating Build: Gitlab</h4>

<p>First thing is to create a new project next choose create build configuration for your new project. Since source is on GitLab you need to check version control settings inside teamcity. Make sure your settings are similar to mine.</p>

<p>You might tell from screenshot that our team city build will monitor dev branch of our project and as soon as new commit will arrive we will be notified to process it.</p>

<p>Now we need to configure build steps right now I only have two build steps that downloads the code of latest commit and compiles it using the method I have choose. Second step will package the compiled code and pass it on to octopus deployment. You can see my build step configuration from following screenshot.</p>

<p>If you don't see octopack section yet with your teamcity installation you need to install octopack plugin. Installation is dead simple copy Octopus.TeamCity.zip into teamcity plugins folder (C:\ProgramData\JetBrains\TeamCity\plugins) then restart Teamciy windows service and refresh your browser you will have octopack section like screenshot.</p>

<h3>Installing octopack</h3>

<p>Installation is dead simple once you have installed the OctopusDeploy server. You can run a tenticle setup on any deployment server (Staging, Testing, Production).</p>

<p>Let's confgiure our project inside octopusDeploy now. Create a new project and name it.</p>

<p>Create a new envoirnment and make sure add your tenticle or deployemnet server to that envoirnment. I have one envoirnment called development but later on I will add more like staging and production.</p>

<p>Octopusdeploy api key by going inside user.</p>

<p>We need to tell octopus how to download teamcity output for that you need to visit back teamcity and configure a nuget feed.</p>

<p>Add nuget feed of teamcity with teamcity credentials. test by
searching packages. Make sure your teamcity has nuget feed available.</p>

<p>While are pecies of puzzle are in their place we can now define the deployment procoess for our project. Octopusdeploy breaks process into steps that you need to define and configured.</p>

<p>We start with our first step called deploy and like it's name it deploys the latest build from teamcity to any envoirnment we have pick.</p>

<h4>Slack Notifications</h4>

<h4>Smoke Testing Deployment</h4>

<p><img src="http://media.giphy.com/media/c3LrSypJkaj0A/giphy.gif" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.simonstratford.com/wp-content/uploads/game-of-thrones-tyrion-lanister.gif" /></p>

<h3>Teamcity</h3>

<p><img src ="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-UE-hPQxWaFM/VK08NeMJOqI/AAAAAAAADk8/OwzNLBeQ9fk/w675-h563-no/jsp-Dev-Configuration----TeamCityOctopus.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src ="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-DxsEE4vWejk/VK08KDHqhGI/AAAAAAAADkM/bokpxHfv0lI/w1044-h492-no/JumpstartPakistan----jsp-Dev----1--31-Dec-14-16-07----Build-Log-%E2%80%94-TeamCity.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-8051eiR2hqQ/VK08LJR0S0I/AAAAAAAADkk/wIEO5eM3Rx8/w1044-h492-no/Plugins-List-%E2%80%94-TeamCity.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-HgycLiQB-VE/VK08HN9MQ3I/AAAAAAAADjk/RzN8533XJkI/w1044-h492-no/Create-Build-Configuration-%E2%80%94-TeamCity.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-gawLVzorkio/VK08JhJiFNI/AAAAAAAADkQ/6Wz8eiDJSn4/w351-h563-no/Edit-VCS-Root----TeamCity.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-Kk6UsR-yd-8/VK08Ij1p8iI/AAAAAAAADj4/9TOuhJi_2S0/w1044-h492-no/Diagnostics---Browse-Data-Directory-%E2%80%94-TeamCity.jpg"/></p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-8ywvuLLHDpg/VK08MbRYi9I/AAAAAAAADk0/LT3lOGdbdfg/w934-h563-no/gitpush.jpg" />
<img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/--M2by-kAbPA/VK08NzqncBI/AAAAAAAADlA/vO2a0vnO9kE/w686-h563-no/jsp-Dev-Configuration----TeamCity_build_step.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/FD74QCTbIywNS-ZKDWKV-3MQz41_8zdgF9gvrhzIcek=w1044-h492-no" /></p>

<p><img src ="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-QgCOHh426Qo/VK08KQ8becI/AAAAAAAADkU/JRsK-3fkc6w/w1044-h492-no/JumpstartPakistan-deployment-process---Octopus-Deploy.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src ="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-xUsarFDboeI/VK08KmN0dvI/AAAAAAAADkc/314u0zZYqXA/w1044-h492-no/JumpstartPakistan-variables---Octopus-Deploy_varriables.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-2ncogbfvwlc/VK08LynNuPI/AAAAAAAADks/Mb0RAJnMsJI/w1044-h492-no/TeamCity-Packages---Octopus-Deployfeed.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-izLzdy0drnQ/VK08HOYFABI/AAAAAAAADjs/4hTmdXlhWy4/w347-h562-no/Deploy---Octopus-Deploy_step_deploy.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-7BkVrcQkcc4/VK08HwRAiKI/AAAAAAAADj0/DNP6ANsOWvk/w1044-h492-no/Development-settings---Octopus-Deploy.jpg" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MongoDB Setup On Windows 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2013/10/22/mongodb-setup-on-windows-8/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-22T13:15:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2013/10/22/mongodb-setup-on-windows-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am very much into learning new tools and burning hours of my life trying to figure them out. To track whats new on development horizon and technology I tend to keep my eyes on sessions, conferences, blogs and screen-casts.</p>

<p>In past few days I wanted to explore no-sql options two in particular RavenDB and MongoDB. I have successfully completed the environment setup for raven but didn't use it in any project until now. On the other hand I have built a new website for my current employer using MVC4 and MongoDB. I have learned a a lot and in this blog post I will share few commands to setup mongoDB and deploy it on remote server.</p>

<p>You can download MongoDb zip file from http://www.mongodb.org/downloads. I picked 64bit version of it.</p>

<h2>Installing MongoDb as windows service</h2>

<p>To install MongoDB using your command prompt navigate to the bin folder in my case it was on following path:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;pre>&lt;code>D:\mongodb\bin&gt;
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Then run following command to install it</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;pre>&lt;code>D:\mongodb\bin&gt;mongod --dbpath=D:\mongodb --logpath=D:\mongodb\log.txt --install
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Then you can goto windows services and look for MongoDB service and simply start it. If you face any error during installation make sure you launch command prompt as administrator and log.txt file used in above command do exists in your hard drive.</p>

<p>If for some reason you want to un-install the MongoDB service run following command in command prompt after stopping service from system services.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;pre>&lt;code>D:\mongodb\bin&gt;mongod --remove
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<h2>GUI to manage MongoDB</h2>

<p>You can interact with MongoDb database and collections using command prompt it will make you master of the little quires against small frequent tasks. In my case I wanted some simple GUI to perform simple tasks and I came across <a href="http://robomongo.org/">RoboMongo</a>.</p>

<p>Installation is simple once this tool is installed and you have your MongoDb service up and running. click on the create button showing in following screen.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-W5SYuoYBfqE/UmZNepJZPkI/AAAAAAAACcQ/LVaMJiW2k50/w668-h410-no/roboCreate.jpg" alt="Robo Mongo Connection Screen" /></p>

<p>Proceed with defaults in address I have localhost and using port 27017. After connection is created you can click on the connect button and it will show you following screen listing with your databases and collections.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/fJjuZWRgwzWSRNwF0HzVw4bJ8JryEKLuAwWWIaKlfEY=w1183-h737-no" alt="Robo Mongo Showing Databases and Collections" /></p>

<h2>Deployment</h2>

<p>After completing v1.0 I have been asked to deploy our new web site on remote server. Asp.net deployment was not a big deal but to deploy local MongoDb database onto remote I had to read about two commands <em>mongodump</em> and <em>mongorestore</em></p>

<p>First to create a backup file of my local mongoDB database I run following command</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;pre>&lt;code>mongodump --db DBName
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Above command will generate called DBName under MongoDB_Installation_Folder/bin/dump inside generated folder you will find <em>.bson</em> files for all the collections your database contains. I have uploaded this folder on remote server.</p>

<p>Now to restore MongoDB on remote server I used mongorestore command syntax is simple you need to supply foldername/dbname to restore</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;pre>&lt;code>mongorestore dump/DBName
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Once restore is completed successfully you can check your database on remote using RoboMongo.</p>

<p>I hope this will help someone starting with MongoDB thank you for reading my blog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
