<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: browsers | Najam Sikander Awan]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/categories/browsers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-30T22:28:47+05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[najam sikander awan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Chrome Bookmarks?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2008/09/27/google-chrome-bookmarks/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-27T17:38:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2008/09/27/google-chrome-bookmarks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>hi friends</p>

<p>You know google chrome is out and everyone was so excited about that including me as a very passionate user i tried to do all of the things now in chrome i have imported my firefox settings (bookmarks) into chrome. All bookmarks are showing good I liked that but shortly I needed to perform a simple task in chrome that is "searching for a bookmarked site among all the bookmarks i have" and till now i don't know how to search for my bookmark in mighty chrome.</p>

<p>So if anyone of you know how to seach bookmarks in chrome please let me know. And one more thing what about tags how can I tag my pages?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[safari on windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2007/06/11/safari-on-windows/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-11T22:21:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2007/06/11/safari-on-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>hi guyz
believe or not safari famous apple browser new beta version is here for both mac and windows users yes u heard it all right its for windows too i have downloaded it and installed it and it works great for me.</p>

<p>Since i never used it and i am a big fan of firefox i am finding a little difficulty to find the features i am used to with like a home page icon history cleaner,no enter or go button,full screen and how to auto complete url for .com and other domains.</p>

<p>I guess it will take time to get used to with that but one thing is for sure this is very good move made by apple they should launch more products for window users.</p>

<p>Regards
Najam Sikander Awan</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Firefox Extensions]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2005/12/26/my-firefox-extensions/"/>
    <updated>2005-12-26T21:29:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2005/12/26/my-firefox-extensions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well here is a random list of all the extensions for my firefox<br />1. All in one gesture<br />2. Session Saver<br />3. Ad Block <br />4. Fasterfox<br />5. Reload Every<br />6. Groowe Searchtoobar<br /><br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modify Firefox 1.5 to work with all extensions]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2005/12/02/modify-firefox-15-to-work-with-all-extensions/"/>
    <updated>2005-12-02T13:12:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2005/12/02/modify-firefox-15-to-work-with-all-extensions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For all of those who just downloaded Firefox 1.5 and canât get your extensions to work. This is a simple modification of Firefoxâs configuration to trick the extensions to work. No need to manually edit the extensions to get them to work. Currently all the extensions I use work except the bookmark sync extension that I so dearly want to.</p>


<p>1. At the location bar, enter: about:config. This will show you a list of Firefox internal preferences.<br />
2. Right-click on the list, select New &gt; String<br />
Enter âapp.extensions.versionâ? (without quotes) for the preference name.<br />
3. Then, enter â1.0â? (without quotes) as the value for app.extensions.version.<br />
4. Restart Firefox 1.5, then enable those disabled Firefox extensions.<br />
5. Restart Firefox 1.5 again to active the extensions. Done.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speed Up Firfox]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2005/12/01/speed-up-firfox/"/>
    <updated>2005-12-01T00:12:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2005/12/01/speed-up-firfox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong> Here's something for broadband people that will really speed Firefox up:<br />
</strong><br />
1.Type "about:config" into the address bar and hit return. Scroll down and look for the following entries:</p>


<p>network.http.pipelining<br />
network.http.proxy.pipelining<br />
network.http.pipelining.maxrequests</p>


<p>Normally the browser will make one request to a web page at a time. When you enable pipelining it will make several at once, which really speeds up page loading.</p>


<p>2. Alter the entries as follows:</p>


<p>Set "network.http.pipelining" to "true"</p>


<p>Set "network.http.proxy.pipelining" to "true"</p>


<p>Set "network.http.pipelining.maxrequests" to some number like 30. This means it will make 30 requests at once.</p>


<p>3. Lastly right-click anywhere and select New-&gt; Integer. Name it "nglayout.initialpaint.delay" and set its value to "0". This value is the amount of time the browser waits before it acts on information it receives.</p>


<p>If you're using a broadband connection you'll load pages MUCH faster now!
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
