<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | Najam Sikander Awan]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T21:49:43+05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[najam sikander awan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[playing with octopress blogging]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2013/04/22/playing-with-octopress-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T20:12:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2013/04/22/playing-with-octopress-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I first came to know about octopress from yayquery episode in which rebbeca murphy mentioned she has moved her blog form wordpress to octopress and she is very happy with that. At that time I didn't paid any attention to this.</p>

<p>But today I suddenly started to play with it and I liked few things I learn along the way and that kept me going till I have imported all of my posts from wordpress to github pages.</p>

<p>I have read following pages form octopress documentation for configuration and blogging:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/configuring/">configuring octopress</a></li>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/">blogging with octopress</a></li>
<li>To migrate your wordpress posts to markdown files i have used <a href="https://github.com/theaob/wpXml2Jekyll">wpxml2jekyll</a></li>
<li>To integrate twitter into your octopress blog sidebar read <a href="http://blog.jmac.org/blog/2013/03/30/putting-twitter-back-into-octopress/">put twitter back into sidebar</a>
To link your octopress setup with github you have to run following this will ask for your user/organization repository.</li>
</ul>


<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;/p>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;pre>&lt;code>rake setup_github_pages
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&lt;p></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Next you need to do following two commands to generate site from octopress and upload it to github repo.</p>

<pre><code>rake generate
rake deploy
</code></pre>

<p>I will have few things in mind to discover about octopress</p>

<ul>
<li>q: how to customize the styles/layout?</li>
<li>q: how to make twitter work in sidebar?</li>
<li>q: how to make rake preview to work against current copy in master branch?</li>
<li>q: how to make it work against blog.najamsikander.com</li>
<li>q: how to get my comments against each post from discuss?</li>
</ul>


<p>I will keep updating this post while discovering work around. I guess i will be ditching wordpress soon after finding all the answers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highlight your code with wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2009/02/03/highlight-your-code-with-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-03T05:00:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2009/02/03/highlight-your-code-with-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi guys,
Today I have installed a new wordpress plugin called <strong>"Code Snippet"</strong> and it support code highlight for many languages try this out you would love it. <a title="Download code snippet" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/codesnippet-20/" target="_blank">Download it now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wordpress wamp and permalinks]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2009/01/27/wordpress-wamp-and-permalinks/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-27T02:28:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2009/01/27/wordpress-wamp-and-permalinks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>hi everyone</p>

<p>I am posting after a long time guess I was super busy :) well first things first I have installed wordpress 2.7 on my hosting and imported all the data from my blog running at http://najam.wordpress.com.</p>

<p>Now a days I am busy with developing themes with wordpress and since I am stuck with windows wamp is a choice for me. One problem I run into is if I try to put custom structure for my permalinks to have more seo friendly blog it fails to show the post or page :( . Anyone know whats the problem? And even if I do this for this blog you reading it would fail to show the page/post that includes the front page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tags!! welcome]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2007/09/30/tags-welcome/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-30T20:05:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2007/09/30/tags-welcome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With wordpress 2.3 codename dexter wordpress bloggers finally have their hands on most waited features <strong>"Tags". </strong>Tags are very much like categories but little convenient  then categories. Tags come handy when you are posting and you can put tags onto your post by just typing tag name and comma separate them whereas if you want post under multiple categories you have to select the check boxes for that.<span style="font-size:12pt;font-family:'Times New Roman';">  </span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing yahoo 360]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2006/01/28/testing-yahoo-360/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-28T16:48:00+05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.najamsikander.com/blog/2006/01/28/testing-yahoo-360</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you ever tried yahoo 360 well I just created a yahoo 360 blog for testing and I must admit that yahoo 360 offering more options then wordpress and can comptiable to your existing blogs (wordpress or other famious blogs) and to your flicker photostream. You can checkout my yahoo 360 beta blog ;) at <a href="http://360.yahoo.com/dragona_eyez">http://360.yahoo.com/dragona_eyez</a><br />and please leave your comments. They are needed to improve my writing skills :).<br /><br /><br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
